Guide to the Carlton E. Morse Oral history interview by Eugene D. Carlisle and related correspondence and reference material, 1936-1981
Department of Special Collections
Morse,Carlton E., Oral history interview by Eugene D. Carlisle and related correspondence and reference material,
1936-1981
M0770
Morse, Carlton E.
4 linear ft
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Forty oral history interviews (tapes and transcripts) conducted between 1970 and 1975, legal releases, correspondence and related materials. The collection also contains address and cast lists for ONE MAN'S FAMILY, original scripts for August 16 and 19, 1936, and program ephemera. There are newsclippings "Random reflections," written by Morse, 1972-1974, photographs of Morse and his family, and a video "Good old days of radio," narrated by Steve Allen, n.d.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Cypress College, 1995.
Biography
A well-known radio dramatist, Carlton E. Morse joined production staff of NBC in 1930. His scripting credits include One Man's Family (1932-1959), I Love a Mystery (1939-1944), and other programs.
Eugene D. Carlisle was Professor of History at Cypress College, Cypress California, and conducted the interviews from 1970 through 1975.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Forty oral history interviews (tapes and transcripts) conducted between 1970 and 1975, legal releases, correspondence and related materials. The collection also contains address and cast lists for ONE MAN'S FAMILY, original scripts for August 16 and 19, 1936, and program ephemera. There are newsclippings "Random reflections," written by Morse, 1972-1974, photographs of Morse and his family, and a video "Good old days of radio," narrated by Steve Allen, n.d.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Allen, Steve.; Amerine, Maynard.; Andrews, William J.; Beeson, Ellis.; Berwin, Bernice.; Canfield, Roger.; Carlisle, Eugene D.; Carter, Wayne.; Christy, Helen E.; Conners, John L.; Dahlstead, Dresser.; Gilman, Page.; Hoag, Vinnie Sheer.; Loofbourow, Arlene.; Mallette, Margaret.; Merriam, Esther.; Morse, Anne.; Morse, Melvin M.; Morse, Patricia.; Peebler, Gladys.; Raffetto, Michael.; Bohemian Club.; Radio--History.; Radio plays--Production and direction.; Audiotapes.; Photoprints.; Video recordings.; Good Old Days of Radio.; One Man's Family.; aThe Women in my House.
Collection Contents
- Interview transcript (1): Helen E. Christy (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Interview transcript (2): Helen E. Christy (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Interview transcript (3): Helen E. Christy (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Interview transcript (4): Helen E. Christy (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Interview transcript (5): Dresser Dahlstead (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Interview transcript (6): Dresser Dahlstead (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Interview transcript (7): Dresser Dahlstead (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Interview transcript (8): Carlton E. Morse (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Interview transcript (9): Carlton E. Morse (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Interview transcript (10): Carlton E. Morse (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Interview transcript (11): Carlton E. Morse (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Interview transcript (12): Carlton E. Morse (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Interview transcript (13): Patricia A. Morse (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Interview transcript (14): Noel Morse Canfield, Roger Canfield (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Interview transcript (15): Prof. L. Loofbourow, Arlene Loofbourow (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Interview transcript (16): Jennings Historical Society - Bayhi, Hoag and Necessary (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Interview transcript (17): Vinnie Sheer Hoag (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Interview transcript (18): John L. Conners (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Interview transcripts (19): Margret Malette (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Interview transcript (20): Geo. Albert Morse (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Interview transcript (21): Wilmer W. Morse (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Interview transcripts (22): Geo. (Harry) Morse (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Interview transcript (23): Lucile (Morse) and Ernest Chastain (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Interview transcript (24): Michael Rafetto (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Interview transcript (25): Michael Rafetto (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Interview transcript (26): Ann Morse (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Interview transcript (27): Ann Morse (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Interview transcript (28): Page Gilman (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Interview transcript (29): Wm. J. Andrews (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Interview transcript (30): Wm. J. Andrews (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Interview transcript (31): Bernice Berwin (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Interview transcript (32): Carrie Morse Lloyd (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Interview transcript (33): Gladys Peebler (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Interview transcript (34): Jazz Harold Weise (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Interview transcript (36): Dr. Maynard Amerine (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Interview transcript (37): Ellis Beeson (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Interview transcript (38): Melvin E. Morse (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Interview transcript (39-40): Esther Merriam/ Wayne Carter (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Interview transcript (41): Esther Merriam/ Wayne Carter (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Master list (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Interviewee names, corresponding tape and transcript number and date of interview Master list -- length and recording quality of tapes
- Letter of introduction for Eugene D. Carlisle from Carlton E. MorseMarch 26, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Interview agreement forms (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Legal forms [1 of 3] (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Legal forms [2 of 3] (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Legal forms [3 of 3] (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Correspondence of Eugene Carlisle: Outgoing correspondence 1971 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Carlton Morse, March 3
- Correspondence of Eugene Carlisle: Incoming correspondence1971 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Carlton Morse, November 10
- Correspondence of Eugene Carlisle: Outgoing correspondence1972 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Carlton Morse, March 3 -- Carlton Morse draft, June 29
- Correspondence of Eugene Carlisle: Incoming and outgoing correspondence 1972 regarding Jennings, Lousiana, Morse's birthplace1972 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Letter to Eugene D. Carlisle from Valerie Jean Conner July 11 -- Draft letter to Connor from Carlisle, n.d. -- Louisiana State Department of Health, New Orleans: birth certificate forms for Morse -- Letter to Carlisle from Meredith Necessary, Board President of Jennings Public Library, August 5 -- Letter to Meredith Necessary from L.L. Morse, August 30 -- Letter to Eugene Carlisle from Hilda Bayhi and newsclippings from Jennings Daily News, 1972 -- Letter from Carlisle to Mayor of Jennings, July 6 -- List of members of Morse and Grubb families. -- Excerpts and copies from The Birth of Jennings, by Walter D. Morse
- Photographs of Morse and Grubb Jenning homes (4) -- Photographs of Jennings and Morse's mother as a young woman (9 4x5 and 9 duplicate 10x10) (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Correspondence of Eugene Carlisle: Outgoing correspondence1973 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  Carlton Morse, March 16 -- Anne Morse, March 29 -- Michael Raffetto, March 29 -- Lucile Morse Chastain, March 29 -- Mrs. Brook Berlin (Bernice Berwin), March 29 -- Harry Morse, March 29 -- Wilmer W. Morse, March 29 -- Patricia Morse, April 24 -- William Andrew, May 8 -- Bernice Berwin, May 8 -- Page Gillman, May 17 -- Bernice Berwin, May 23
- Correspondence of Eugene Carlisle: Incoming correspondence 1973 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  Carleton Morse, April 1 -- Wilmer Morse, April 3 -- Michael Raffetto, April 4 -- Lucile Morse Chastain, April 6 -- Anne Morse, April 7 -- Bernice Berwin, April 26 -- William Andrew, May 16 -- Bernice Berwin, May 19 -- Page Gilman, May 21
- Correspondence of Eugene Carlisle: Outgoing correspondence1974 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  Helen E. Christy, August 8 -- Maynard Amerine, September 13 -- Wilmer Morse, September 13 -- Anne Morse, September 16 -- Michael Raffetto, September 16 -- Maynard Amerine, September 27 -- Michael Raffetto, September 27 -- Anne Morse, September 27 -- Jazz Harold Weise, September 27 -- Jazz Harold Weise, October 4 -- William Andrew, October 4 -- Carlton Morse, October 14 -- Mrs. H.P. Groesbeck, October 15 -- Mrs. Carrie Lloyd, October 15 -- Dr. Maynard Amerine, October 24 -- William Andrew, November 9 -- Jazz Weise, December 6 -- Michael Raffetto, December 6
- Correspondence of Eugene Carlisle: Incoming correspondence1974 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Anne Morse, September 17 -- Michael Raffetto, September 20 -- Maynard Amerine, Septmeber 25 -- Wilmer Morse, September 28 -- J. Harold Weise, September 30 -- Anne Morse, October 2 -- Michael Raffetto, October 3 -- Maynard Amerine, October 18 -- Leon T. Loofbourow, December 15
- Correspondence of Eugene Carlisle: Outgoing correspondence1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Michael Raffetto, January 8 -- Mrs. Jack Macdonald, January 8 -- Mrs. Jack Macdonald, February 7 -- Bernice Berlin Berwin, April 4 -- George Harris Morse, April 4 -- Helen E. Christy, April 4 -- Carlton Morse, July 7 -- Mrs. Jack Macdonald, July 7 -- Esther Merriman, July 7 -- Melvin Morse, July 7 -- Melvin Morse, July 20
- Correspondence of Eugene Carlisle: Incoming correspondence1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Mrs. Jack Macdonald, January 15 -- Bernice Berwin, April 23 -- Melvin Morse, July 16 -- Esther Merriam, July 18 -- Melvin Morse, July 28
- "One Man's Family " address listDecember 17, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- "One Man's Family " cast listMay 21, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- "The Women in My House" cast listMay 21, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Original script of "One Man's Family"August 16, 19, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  With letter from Mrs. Macdonald to Michael Raffetto and letter from Raffetto to Carlisle
- Mother Barbour's (Minetta Ellen) Chatter with the Batter cookbook1948 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Promotional for "One Man's Family"
- Father Barbour's (J. Anthony Smythe) "This I Give"1948 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Photoslides (4) from "One Man's Family"n.d. (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Newspaper and magazine articles on Carlton E. Morse 1939-1951 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Newspaper and magazine articles on Carlton E. Morse 1966-1976 and n.d. (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Newspaper articles: The Country Almanac (Woodside, CA) "Random Reflections" by Carlton Morse (1972-1974) (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Newsclippings on "Old Radio"1977, 1978, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- The North American Radio Archives...First Annual Tribute Dinner; Guest of Honor: Carlton Morse June 2 1973 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Photographs (11) taken at dinner with identifying list
- Photographs (7) of Carlton and family (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Bohemian Club memorabilia (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Carlton Morse obituary (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Michael Raffetto obituary (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Letters and receipt of donations to Oakland MuseumMay 9, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Audiotapes of interviews 1-31 (Box 4)
- Audiotapes of interviews 32-41 and miscellaneous cassettes (4) (Box 5)
- Duplicate master tapes of interviews (closed) [1 of 2] (Box 6)
- Duplicate master tapes of interviews (closed) [2 of 2] (Box 7)
- Master 1/4 in. magnetic tapes of interviews [1 of 2] (Box 8)
- Master 1/4 in. magnetic tapes of interviews [2 of 2] (Box 9)
- "Good Old Days of Radio" narrated by Steve Allen, n.d. [1" video tape] (Box 10)